Murder of a Cat is a thriller, comedy, mystery film directed by Gillian Greene.
When someone murders his beloved cat, Clinton, an adult child, demands justice.
Taking it upon himself to solve the case, he teams up with an unlikely ally, Greta, and
the two set out to find the culprit lurking in their small suburban town.
But as Clinton searches for the truth, he begins to uncover a
conspiracy that goes far deeper than he anticipated.
Clinton Moisey, played by Fran Kranz.
Greta Chiplinsky, played by Nikki Reed.
Sheriff Frank Hoyle, played by J.K. Simmons.
Yi Kim, played by Leonardo Nam.
Dr. Jag Mundhra, played by Dileep Rao.
Trevor, played by Aidan Andrews.
Murder of a Cat is a 2014 American comedy thriller film directed by
Gillian Greene and starring Fran Kranz, Nikki Reed, J.
Simmons, Dileep Rao, Blythe Danner, and Greg Kinnear.
The film premiered at the 2014 Tribeca Film Festival, and was given a limited theatrical
release in the United States on December 5, 2014, by Gravitas Ventures.
This was Greene's second collaboration with Kranz, Rao, and Simmons.
The first was her directorial debut short film Fanboy.
The film is also the Raimi brothers' second film with Simmons, after the Spider-Man trilogy
(2002–2007), and their second film with Rao, after Drag Me to Hell (2009).
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending and thought_provoking.